now let's do an arrow be timing quiz so
here is again a sequence of instructions
and we want to know when the issue
executes right and commit and we want
some comments here now let's say that an
ad takes one cycle multiplication takes
two cycles and divide takes four cycles
and in this processor we can broadcast
one add or subtract result from the add
subtract unit and one multiplication
divide result per cycle so if both the
add unit and the multiply unit have a
result available they can actually
broadcast them in the same cycle and
this processor can also commit up to two
instructions per cycle so two
instructions can commit in a cycle if
both of them can commit and we know Fria
reservation station at dispatch so let's
look at what should be happening here we
know that this instruction issues in
cycle 1 begin execution in cycle 2 it
will begin execution in cycle 2 and then
four cycles later in cycle 6 it's going
to write the result and it's going to
commit in cycle 7 so the question for
you is for this multiplication when does
it issue execute right and commit you
can write your answers here so pretty
much what should go here
you should write here here here and here